within Tessl we talk a lot about communication that's become
our biggest bottleneck, is keeping up with the rate of change of the code base.
I think for the last 3 or 4 weeks straight, we've shipped 30% more
PR than we did the week before.
And it's like not stopping.
And so people are saying like, I don't even know
what the person next to me is working on, let alone like the rest of the team.
Oh, no. Oh!
Welcome, everybody.
My name is Dru.
I am the head of product and design here at Tessl.
Before I took over product, I actually joined Tessl
about a year, year and a half ago as our head of AI research.
So I sort of moonlight both in ML engineering as well as product and design.
My talk today is going to be more focused on the actual engineering aspects of it.
So I'm going to walk through harness engineering as a technique for anyone
who feels just absolutely dizzy by the pace of change in the industry.
I made this talk like two and a half weeks ago, and I think
there's already three new terms that describe harness engineering.
There's loop engineering, there's software factories,
there's meta engineering, all of them roughly the same.
I'll try to disambiguate some of the terms.
I got tired of updating the slide for every new one, so I'll just sort of
use them interchangeably before I get started.
This is a moderately advanced talk.
It should be useful to everybody here, but in terms of when you should apply
some of the techniques that I'm going to talk through,
I'd say you want to start on harness engineering in these kind of topics.
Once you've got pretty good at using interactive coding agent sessions.
And so what do I mean by pretty good?
One is you should be at a point where you're
pretty regularly using a few sessions at a time in parallel.
So you're not just watching one agent work all the time.
Second, you should be at a point where agents are pretty frequently
one shotting easy tasks and with some degree of frequency.
Also one shotting medium tasks.
That doesn't mean like it just outputs code,
but like you don't have to intervene as the agent runs.
And then finally, everything I want to talk about here is a new way of working.
We'll get into it,
but a lot of it is actually team and organizational transformation.
So it does also require a bit of buy in.
Like it's not a zero cost technique though.
I'll talk about how you can make it as cheap as possible before I get in there.
I'm kind of just curious how many folks here feel like this describes them.
Man, the industry move so fast these days.
Can you, just as a crazy thing like agents got good what, like six months ago?
And to go from technology gets good to like basically
the whole room is at an intermediate to advanced usage.
Again. Wild. Okay. That's great.
So you'll all probably will like what I'm about to talk about.
If you don't, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
So like I said, we're going to use terms interchangeably.
Ultimately the techniques I'm going to talk about here
are how you start moving towards building a software factory
or in essence, delegating more of your work to agents.
So when we talk about what is the software factory, why you would want one?
Is it the end of the craft we know and love?
No, I don't think so.
Then harness engineering.
What are the actual techniques you use to build up a software factory?
The components that as you're doing
harness engineering, you will be using, you'll be reaching for to do your work.
And then because I have a job, I have to tell you a little bit
about how Tessl helps with all of this.
But I promise everything before
that is just general techniques so you don't have to use Tessl.
I think Tessl is pretty great, but you can do whatever you want,
okay.
Software factories, what are they?
I try to keep this pretty simple.
So ultimately, the sort of the end game of a software factory is one
in which you have an agent system, a series of
loops that build the entire end product that you ship
to users, customers, anything like that, and where humans are doing
all of their work shaping tickets, shaping tasks for the factory,
and then working to improve the autonomy,
automation and quality of the system.
So think of it as we're monitoring the processes.
The processes are building the widgets.
You may ask, what do you mean autonomy, automation, quality, etc..
So first, to give you all a framework, Tassell ourselves,
we dogfood our own product.
We are developing, I'd say predominantly via a software factory.
At this point, what we have learned is that there are three
big dimensions that you want to track in your
rollouts of agents before
software factories, but then as you move into software factories, for sure.
The first is autonomy, which you can think of as how many course
corrections do you have to give an agent to get to the right answer?
You can.
This one can be very easily monitored, right.
It's like literally how many human turns did it take?
Or if it puts up a PR, how many comments were needed on the PR?
This is a metric that you're going to want to track.
You're going to want to drive down.
You're going to sort of go in this in this order as you build.
Automation is related but not the same.
So automation is how much oversight do agents need.
So you could have a world.
You can have a world where agents are actually very autonomous.
You don't actually have to course correct them,
but they're not automated because you don't trust them yet.
So you're still reviewing all of their work,
you're still checking their shoulder, you're just not making any corrections.
And that's actually one of the major ruts we see people get into is
they could be delegating a lot more to agents,
but for a variety of reasons that are not yet able to.
And so they end up getting review as a bottleneck is one of the first things
you'll hear
as people really have unlocked autonomy but have not unlocked automation.
And then finally, quality. This is the easy one.
This is just like, is your product still good?
As you start to ship more with agents you don't want to be shipping slop.
At Tessl, we believe that actually software
factories and agentic coding is a gateway to much higher quality
in the software that you produce, which I'll talk about in a minute.
And by a minute I mean right now.
So thinking about a software factory like you are
working through these metrics, you're trying to delegate more to an agent.
Why would you want to?
Why would you think that that is a smart thing to do.
Besides, you want your stock price to go up
because you said you have an AI strategy first. Yes.
What most people talk about higher velocity.
I think this is where most people start.
This will pay out pretty quickly.
Like the minute you unlock a good amount of autonomy in your system,
you will find that it is faster
to write code through agents than it is to type the code yourself.
But the big one, and I think this is when we we're
in a bit of a transition period, is unlocking
actually higher quality to the code that you ship as well.
And so right now there's this very big trade off people talk about like,
oh yeah, you can go faster, but aren't you shipping slop?
Or the agents are writing weird code.
Some of that is definitely true.
And we'll talk about how you can mitigate that with harness engineering.
I want to take a step back.
Let's look maybe six months out, maybe six weeks out.
Who knows the rate of things.
There are two big things, in my opinion, and my years of software
engineering that lead to low quality software.
The first is just incomplete.
Things get through review because people are either moving quickly, or
they themselves are not versed in the system that they are reviewing.
They look with a certain bias.
And so this is an area where coding agents, when you sort of
unlocked a good agent code review process,
they're like the ultimate code reviewer, right?
They're tireless.
They'll check everything.
You can have 15 of them checking every lens very specifically
like security, reuse, usability, etc.
but also you can be running like an agentic QA.
You can be having an agent poke around with your like,
the amount of energy and tokens that you can devote to
review is no longer capped by like a human bashing their head against the wall.
Like I'm tired of reviewing code.
And so there is, I think, as a starting point,
and we're starting to see this
with companies that are towards the front end of a agentic adoption, companies
like intercom, where they're actually noticing a decrease
in bugs that get through review because they have scaled up
how much effort they're putting into their review process.
The second one, though, is that actually,
in my experience, most bugs in software
or known about and they are just P2 on a backlog somewhere.
We just don't have time to fix it. It's not a priority.
User flow.
Oftentimes we knew the bug and we shipped with it anyways
because it was too expensive to fix.
And so one of, in my opinion, the most exciting things about
as you are able to delegate more work to agents
is that the idea of a backlog kind of goes away.
Not entirely, but your capacity is so much larger.
Your ability to just fix all the issues you find goes way, way up.
And so I think as we get through some of the teething pains of working on
software factories,
we're actually going to see a world where software is much better.
And in particular, it's much better for niche use cases, like people who
otherwise would not have been a priority to fix their issues in the past.
Third, a software factory
because by definition, you're not gate kept on who can write code anymore.
You can do broader exploration.
You can bring in people from your GTM teams from design.
We had somebody from our people ops
team land their first production PR a week and a half ago.
It was pretty exciting.
And then and this is the one for me, that's just kind of like a more fun way
to work in my opinion.
I when I write software, I know there is something
this really fun about, like a well crafted module, a well crafted function.
We all are guilty of it.
But for me it's like the architecture.
It's the system design.
It is like, how will this thing scale over time?
And that's what I'm going to show in a minute.
I think all of that still exists in the world of factory building.
And in fact, you spend almost all of your time doing that work.
So I think even if everything I said
before did not exist, like your velocity is
the same, your quality is the same, the same people are building it.
I would still choose to build with a factory over traditional coding.
Your mileage may vary on that.
Personally, I like that.
Okay, final question.
Some folks may be asking should you build a software factory?
Given how you all raise your hands, you already are.
So software factory is not like a once
like a like rip it and then ship something new.
Software factory is an incremental process where you just identify workflows,
put them in a box that is legible to an agent, run it interactively
a few times to build confidence and then automate it right.
It's best done one workflow at a time,
and just incrementally building towards higher
and higher levels of automation, higher and higher levels of autonomy.
So I would argue, yeah, just how much what percent factory do
you want to be is a better question than should I be building a factory?
Okay.
Let's talk harness engineering, loop engineering, meta engineering.
This as we are seeing it within Tessl, I think this is sort of becoming
a norm across the industry is sort of the new form of
engineering, which is instead of focusing on writing code,
instead of focusing on watching an agent write code and correct its mistakes,
you instead focus on building and monitoring loops that are themselves
reviewing the code, reviewing the health of your system, etc.
so what do I mean by loop?
There are three big ones that you need to think about,
and hopefully by the end of this talk
you will feel like they're all pretty approachable.
So we'll start in the center.
You have the inner loop, which you can think of as
the oh, I'm sorry, go ahead and take your photo.
So the inner loop is what drives autonomy.
This is what helps the agent actually get to the right answer on its first try.
So the inner loop is the kind of stuff you're used to developing against, right?
It's your unit tests.
It's your linter. It is manual verification.
Before you push up the PR, using your own eyeballs to look at the code.
Right.
All of these things are like relatively quick checks that are cheap.
You're on them over and over again, and you just sort of hillclimb
against the results.
So if you've ever told your agent to use red, green, TDD,
anything like that, you've been working on the inner loop.
The biggest difference between like the inner loop for yourself
and the inner loop for an agent is that now unit tests and linters,
you don't have to write them, you don't have to maintain them.
And so this is I think one of the first unlocks is to realize
you can be so much more annoying with your inner loop.
Now, like Max pedantic on the linting, you can have specific rules
that check that certain modules don't import other modules.
The kind of stuff you would have told yourself in the past,
this is going to bit rot.
Don't do this.
Everyone hates this now.
It's like the minute it fails and agent sees it, realizes it, fixes it.
And so just basically every time you see an agent make a mistake,
you should be thinking,
how do I put this into a check so that it never happens again?
Right.
And you're going to end up with just massive linting, massive test suites.
And over time you'll want to strip some of them out.
So you want a process to sort of reevaluate if you need them.
But I think this is like
a big change in how we view the tests and the linting that we we write.
Also, how easy is your product to use by an agent?
Is another one here right.
Can it access it via CLI or things like that.
The outer loop is what builds automation.
So this is ideally a set of slower, more in-depth checks
that build up your confidence in this
PR is correct so that you have to spend less time
actually reviewing every piece of the code.
And so the bread and butter starting point for this is an agentic code review.
You want as much as you can.
I think Claude code does the estimate like $25 for a PR review.
That sounds crazy.
But then also you think like the time a human would spend.
Maybe it's not as crazy at Tessl.
We think you can get it a lot cheaper, so don't worry $25.
It's not the going rate of PR review, but you get a sense
that these things are more expensive, they're more involved.
A lot of what we've found that works really well here is actually pulling down
into like a into a box, build your product, run it, have the agent
click through, take screenshots,
show you the thing in action so that you can review that.
I think Cursor has a tool to do this as well.
Anything you can do that doesn't make sense to run as the agent builds,
but that you would want to look at to give you confidence that the thing works.
This is your outer loop.
Then finally, the meta loop
is basically everything I just said on autopilot.
And so you will start with the inner loop.
You will build that up.
Then you will move to getting your code review, getting your agent QA,
all of that nice and tidy.
And then you're going to get really, really tired of doing all of that.
And you will start setting up loops of agents that watch it for you.
So you'll have an agent that looks at all the CI checks
from the last week and says, hey, here are three mistakes that kept getting made.
I'm going to add linting rules for them so they don't make it to CI.
Or oh, I noticed that agents made these three mistakes on
like there were comments on the PRs that told the agent, don't do this.
Let me pull back, let me add a skill or let me add unit tests in this area.
And so the meta loop is sort of what feeds back in.
And the meta loop is ultimately where you'll spend most of your time is creating
these sort of like maintenance agents that watch everything else and make changes
that you either review or don't review, depending on your sort of comfort level,
the importance of the part of the tech stack, etc..
Okay,
so hopefully what I just described doesn't seem that complicated, right?
It's mostly have good unit tests, have good linting,
maybe be a little bit more persnickety about what you put into those suites.
And then it's just a lot of like you have a problem, fix it with agents.
Right?
Like the that loop is pretty straightforward.
So why is harness engineering hard.
And the answer is almost exclusively organizational.
It is just a different way of working for a lot of people.
It's not a fun way of working.
And so we'll talk about how to make it fun.
But let's walk through a few of them.
So the first is that knowing how to write a good agent, knowing
when it's time to embrace a new technique versus not, there's just like an ever.
Like I said, the name of this talk has changed four times in two weeks.
The knowledge is constantly changing.
It's annoying to keep up with it. That's not your day job.
You want to focus on shipping features.
Part of that harness engineering often feels like
unplanned work, so you're trying to build a thing.
You file a ticket, the agent picks it up, it starts working.
It breaks.
The answer in harness engineering is don't tell the agent to fix it.
Instead, stop.
Throw that PR away.
Go back and think like what could have made it
so the agent wouldn't have made this mistake.
It's going to be a unit test.
It's going to be a skill. It's going to be something like that.
Make that change and then roll the dice again.
And hopefully this time it works.
And if it doesn't, throw that PR away and do another one,
and nobody likes working that way, it's like a slot machine.
It's the worst kind of slot machine.
As part of that.
Then if you are doing this work,
let's say eventually you got to a place where it shipped.
You could have shipped two hours ago if you would have just corrected it.
Right.
And so it's really hard to make the case for no,
let me go do some science instead of launching the feature to customers.
And it's very hard to make that argument to your boss
or to your customers, things like that.
And then finally, just really bad legibility.
Like people will start working with Claude Code.
They're making all these mistakes.
You don't realize
you're all making the same mistake or hitting the same pain points.
And so it's hard to fix it.
It's hard to know that, hey, aren't
we all having a problem with this one area of the code base?
It comes out slowly of people
talking about it, or you realizing certain areas are harder to work in.
It's just hard to fix things quickly.
So there's going to be some pieces
that you want to pull together to make that easier.
And then also I'll talk about
sort of Tessl's design philosophy is to try and make harness
engineering fun and seamless rather than organizational change.
So what are the components that you need to do?
Everything I just described,
but in a way that feels less ad hoc, that feels less painful.
The first, and this is if I had to give like
one piece of advice to anyone, I would start here of like,
you want to level up
how you're using coding agents, just do like this one simple trick.
It's actually not that.
It's like there's a little bit of work to it.
Change how you work with the agents.
So even if you are using Claude Code, codex, whatever
and one shotting everything and you think like,
oh yeah, it's easy, I just paste my prompt in my tab away
I go to something else, it puts up the PR, and then I just go work in the PR
and then I correct it in the session and then keep going.
You like that?
Feels almost the same as I file a ticket.
It works in the background.
It puts up a PR, I leave comments on the PR,
it automatically picks up and makes changes.
Was not I promise you.
It's not like just if you don't believe me, OpenAI
put out a white paper talking about how when they moved like
strictly people who are one shotting tasks from working in an interactive session
where they did not interact at all, to going through tickets and PRs.
They saw five x productivity increase over the course of like 2 to 3 months.
So a lot of the reason this works is because once you start working
in this way, one is it forces you to start getting it
right up front because you can't make quick course corrections.
You can't say, oh, wait, no, don't delete the database, right?
Like you just like if you didn't get it right, it's deleted.
They know it won't delete the database, but also
it puts everything that you interact with the agent in a legible surface.
So you have your tickets and then you have PRs with comments.
It now is very easy to just point
another agent at that and say, hey, fix all the comments from the last week.
Like any recurring tasks or any recurring feedback I've given the agent,
find some improvement to the code base that would fix it.
Put up a PR so it makes the harness engineering loop easier.
But most importantly, remember how I said it
sucks to have to revert the change and try again?
You don't have to anymore.
You just leave comments on the PR,
let it fix it, and then have another process
that comes in in the background and cleans up
and does the harness engineering on your behalf.
Or you can do it yourself, but at least you can pick up
all of the comments that you left.
So this seems like a small thing, but it really is the most crucial starting
unlock to leveling up and working towards more automation.
So once you've got your issue tracker, once you've got PR review
as the main interfaces where you steer and correct
agent work, you're going to start developing lots of workflows.
These will be things like Playbook for adding a feature to the CLI.
It will be features around like how to do
security review, how to write or update your docs.
After a PR lens, you'll start with five and then in a week you'll have 1500.
And they they go like crazy very quickly.
And so you're going to want to think through
what is your process for distributing them to the people on your team.
How do you make sure people have the good ones?
How do you make sure that you're not wasting time
writing the same one over and over again, and that when you update one,
it's benefits go to everybody.
So a registry think like npm for your skills.
Once you have that in place.
I think the sort of trench warfare of software factory is what I call
agent it, which is you will be stunned the number of services
that were dependent on a human logging into something somewhere
and then like not in the project,
but just like a global like, oh yeah, I had access to this feature.
I had access to this database or these logs, and every single
one of those is a type of feature your agent can't work on.
And so this is kind of it's a bit of a slog.
You just got to kind of run through it of put up the PR, put up the issue,
realize agent did something stupid and say like, oh, it needs to,
or oh, it needs to create its spin up its own
sandbox and use playwright CLI so that it can click through the product.
Oh shit, we have no way of logging in without.
So like all that stuff, it's a bit of a sort of whack a mole as you go through,
you're going to want things like a company brain.
How do you put all of the stuff that, you know, like your slack,
your notion or whatever other tools people use?
Not at all.
I don't know, like Google Docs, Quora, things like that.
All your internal services,
you're going to want to give it access for, like debugging production issues.
Probably just read to pull in some of this information,
and then you need environments where the agent can actually run,
because I'm sure many of you have seen the like person walking with laptop open.
Again, I'll say it was really funny to see our head of legal
walking with her laptop open, and she's like, I'm a developer now.
And it was. It was true.
She was shipping like production code,
but ideally in the cloud, not on your laptop.
So you want to have how do you give your agent access to everything?
We've lost something.
I'm sure Claude designed.
Just push some kind of update.
Let's see if this works.
If not, I'll just.
Off the dome. There we go.
Okay, present.
If anyone's not using Claude is, like, not a paid advertisement.
Oh, my God, it's so good for slides.
I'm never making a slide by hand again.
Okay, improve.
Yes, this is right.
This is where it's supposed to be in save state improvement loops.
So this is the final piece.
This is those meta like how do you get to a place where you don't
have to be finding and taking time to fix all of these pieces?
So like I said,
this is where moving to an issue tracker and a PR flow really starts to pay off.
Because now you can start saying things like,
We in Tessl, we call them maintenance agents,
where we say, just look at everything for the last day, like
the agent logs, because they're running
in a cloud environment where we have access to them.
Look at the issues, look at the PR comments, look at CI
checks, and just start proposing fixes and then put up a PR.
If it's in a low risk area, just merge the PR.
If it's in a like important production code path, a human will review it.
This is where you'll get things like
here's the playbook for this kind of feature.
And you can get pretty specific here, right?
Like add a feature to the front end or add a feature to the eval surface
within the front end.
Just anything that helps fix agent output.
But this is also where you can start looking for tasks.
So look at all of the issues, or look at all of the
PR that I put up in the last week, and just tell me things
that I've repeated over the last 90 days or the last two weeks,
whatever you want to say, and just propose automations to me,
like you want to get as much as you can into a world where you are reacting
to suggestions instead of having to have the sort of proactive effort to do it.
Because ultimately, you want to spend your time building features for customers.
You don't want to be doing your own internal development work.
You want to just say like, oh, I wake up in the morning, I've got 2 or 3 PRs.
They look reasonable, I accept them.
I'm a little more AI native than I was yesterday.
Now back to to shipping.
So plays through this part because it's like it's a bit of an ad.
But Tessl helps with all of this.
We sort of moniker ourselves as the platform for building software factories.
If you think of this as you want to delegate more work to AI,
you're going to have lots of problems along the way.
Tessl tries to help you find those problems and then
has tools to make fixing them easy.
Why do you want us?
Well, I think we're cool, but you don't have to use us.
We are.
First of all, we try to be pretty batteries included.
So I mentioned things are changing all of the time.
So we have an agent interface that tries to capture
a lot of the best practices I described. Here.
You can open the Tessl agent.
You can say, hey, help me set up code review and it knows what good
agent code review looks like.
If it changes next week,
it will come in and tell you like, hey, it's changed again, sorry
you're on vacation and it can walk you through all those differences.
So just keeping up with what best practices are ready for prime time.
We also try really, really hard to be very open and modular.
So Tessl's building blocks provide a bunch of rails
to run different workflows, but all of the information
that powers them are standard artifacts that live in your repo.
So, for example, our code review tools, they are powered by skills
that are checked in to your repo.
So if you want to move them to something else, if you want to use them
with a different tool, it's all there. You have control of it.
Nothing sort of like hiding in black boxes.
And because everything is written files, it's
easy to build other automations around it with or without Tessl, right?
You can use the same code review skill in CI
or locally, or you can, just as a team, open it up
and read through it and be like, do we believe in this?
As our style guide?
We also try really hard to do everything in an automated way.
So we'll get to this in a minute.
But the Tessl agent sits there and crawls through and it will do
all of those things I talked about. It will look at your PRs.
It will look at your issues, your CI checks,
and then after it finds improvements, it'll say like,
hey, do you want me to just look every night for you?
And so it'll actually automate itself and then you can go from there.
And we are built around
incremental adoption, so you don't have to get your whole team
bought in to building a software factory and pausing all work for three months.
You can just start doing one thing at a time.
So for the control plane that
I talked about, we have a skills registry or a plug in registry.
This has all the things you would expect baked in.
We have private registries, public registries.
We have quality review.
We can run simulated evals to see if the plugin actually helps the agent.
Security checks, install policies,
everything you'd need to sort of pass workflows around your company.
We have default apps to help
you do the handoff from an issue tracker to PR creation.
So for us, we work internally with linear and GitHub.
We've sort of started there.
So if you're on that stack congratulations.
You have good tool choice.
If you're not you still have good tool choice.
But apps are coming.
We'd love to hear what you're most interested in having us build for you.
And then we have a bunch of out of the box tools for code review,
so we'll help you.
If you're spending too much time on code code review,
we can help you get rid of some of that, that pain point.
See if this works.
Show all controls.
So just very briefly while I talk,
this is the Tessl agent running in our mono repo.
Tessl agent is, in our opinion, the way you make harness engineering fun.
So when you think about it, the first thing that it will do
is it will help discover the work that you can automate.
So we'll look for tasks that you're doing over and over again.
They can be quite simple.
It can be like, oh, every week you bump dependencies
on these certain sets of libraries, but it can be more advanced.
It can be like, oh, once a week you are putting up PRs around test flakiness.
So we've automated an agent that will search for that.
We have maintenance agents that will do a lot of this out of the box,
like keeping your docs up to date, searching
for like areas where agents are wasting a lot of tokens and then suggesting
like you could write a CLI that did this and then agents would know how to use it.
So a lot of things there automatically improving your repos,
sort of like agent readiness by looking at code review feedback
and translating it into improvements in the code base.
And then with Tessl Launch Skill, we give you a sort
of standard way to run any of your favorite coding agents.
So Claude Code, Codex, Cursor, etc..
Cursor CLI in a cloud environment with just like a simple CLI call
that you can put up in GitHub actions so that you can start
getting the benefits of cloud without having to buy into
like a monolithic orchestration framework or anything like that.
Once you have all this in place, this is just a quick recap.
The things you're going to want to look at and drive down as you build towards
a factory is reducing the number of manual takeovers.
So this will be a lot more obvious in this new world,
because it's just the number of human comments on PRs.
Then you're going to want to.
So human PR comments I guess you could also like breaking tickets down, right?
Like the number of times you took a ticket and had to decompose it yourself.
And the agents would also work there, but human touch points in the system.
Then you're going to want to drive up the number of PRs that are initiated by
agents automatically.
This is like a good sign of increasing automation.
It tends to be driven by maintenance agents, so they'll be
most of the pieces will come with, like improving your own code base for agents.
Over time, you can start wiring in things like production logs
and bug reports that then you get a PR put up that you just review.
And then of course you want to improve quality of the code base.
I would argue don't try to do it all at once.
So just aim for don't regress quality too much at first.
The first thing that's going to drive is like,
how the hell do I measure quality?
And so that'll be its own little Don Quixote adventure.
But once you've got that in place, then you want to look at
how do we actually aspire to raise the quality of the code you ship?
Don't just say like, I'm faster, but the code is the same or a little worse.
Like, I think you can aim for something higher.
That's it.
If you want to try the Tessl agent, if you want to try Tessl, scan QR code here.
I think there's also QR codes everywhere.
So you're kind of surrounded.
But that's it.
That's my talk.
Questions.
Building software.
Are you shipping any features when there are no risk involved at all?
It's a great question.
Currently no.
We want to keep a pretty like I said, we're working on the raising the quality
bar. So we still have human code review for anything that touches production,
like an actual end user endpoint.
Few caveats within that.
So we have a bunch of we've tried to sort of slice and dice our code base
so that we have like whole folders or subsections where like this is safe,
like this is the actual harness that orchestrates our agents themselves
or these are docs, these are our unit testing libraries, things like that.
We do allow auto merged PRs into those.
And I think it's already like the majority
of plus the agent finding things and improving in that.
And then we have and this is if you use Tessl
we call it the change risk analyzer.
It's basically a thing
that we'll scan a PR against, a policy that you agree on with your team.
And so a lot of companies are now doing this
where for compliance reasons, you need to be able to point to some artifact
that's like, this is what determines our code quality standards.
So we let you set that policy.
And then an agent will review every PR to say,
does this PR need extensive human review or not.
And so we're starting to experiment with that.
But we are calibrating it right now.
So we're still reviewing everything to decide does it work or not.
I'll just go yeah.
Maybe back there. I have two questions. Okay.
That's okay.
No one. No, I'm just kidding.
Go ahead.
And we were lucky
to get some reviews on models,
but so basically the salesperson told us that they want us
to take the pictures out to the agents
and just take out all the harness and just write beautiful skills.
What's your opinion?
So that's the first question is that command is about cultural wise.
Like recently my boss wrote a PR for a new project
that has like 100 K code with anyone.
Yeah, yeah.
And so in general, if we have a look like no discussion about
how do we shape the culture of coding internally
and how can we put out some kind of guidance internally.
I think if everyone would share the same opinion that you,
you write a proposal and nobody looks at it,
and then you create the tickets and you started working on this.
So what's your opinion on that?
Like how can I change it on the.
Yeah.
Straight to the easy questions.
No. To start with the question
of like skills versus harness you've built around.
It is definitely true that as models come out, you should have some process
for reassessing the glue you've built around the agent.
Shameless plug for Tessl.
We have like an eval suite that can help do this.
We check to see like with and without a plug in. Is it helping?
Is it not helping so that you can sort of pinpoint
like, oh, as we upgrade to fable, could we drop a lot of this stuff?
And it is true that a lot of the skills and hooks
and things like that, that you write
that are specifically around fixing mistakes are short lived, right?
You'll do it for a couple of months, and then you'll strip it out
and you'll move to the next model, and eventually you'll be left with
mostly just describing your workflows, your standards, your policies, the stuff
that's just like how we work here, that any level of intelligence would need.
And so my answer there is mostly just like
have a way of evaluating regularly, like, is this still needed or not?
The second piece about cultural change,
the honest answer is we don't have all the solutions.
Certainly.
And I think it's worth like everybody having grace for everyone around,
like how quickly things are changing.
So within Tessl we talk a lot about communication that's become
our biggest bottleneck, is keeping up with the rate of change of the code base.
I think we're for the last 3 or 4 weeks straight, we've shipped 30% more
PR than we did the week before.
And it's like not stopping.
And so people are saying like, I don't even know
what the person next to me is working on, let alone like the rest of the team.
And but it's just it's a new problem.
There's not really a solution to that yet.
We have to figure it out.
But a couple things that I'll say that have helped with that.
The first is as a starting point, you have to make time for communication, right?
We've gotten used to reading docs, going to meetings,
stuff like that, being sort of required to do your job.
And so we just let that force like, oh, to put your PR up,
you had to talk to these people.
But now people are just pointing agents at everything
and they're like summarizing meetings and summarizing docs without reading them.
And until we find more sustainable approaches,
what I've heard most effective from teams is every Friday, we just have an hour
where everybody sits down and just talks about what they worked on, asks questions,
shares docs with each other and reads them and just we make some space for it.
It's a stopgap for sure.
Like that's not a anything that requires discipline is not a forever solution.
But that's I'd say one the other
the 100,000 line PR is just my condolences.
Like that's pretty rough.
One thing that we've noticed the beginnings of
is that with that risk risk
verifier for PRs, when it says
a human is not needed for this, you can auto merge it in theory, right?
Like we're still reviewing it to make sure it works well. But
if you
codify the right things like a small PR that's contained, that's like
stacked on top instead of being one monolithic PR,
if those become low risk PRs,
then you actually will start shifting everyone's behavior
because they don't want human review, right?
So they're like, oh, let me take this 20,000 line PR and break it up
into a bunch of 200, 300 line PRs because then it'll just auto merge.
And so I think in some of these cases, the answer is
what we've always known is true.
But if you can codify it into practices that make it easier
if you follow them than if you don't follow them,
people will just naturally start doing the right thing.
But these are partial answers.
I think the culture change is something we are all having to figure
out how we work on
C one right here.
I'll repeat the question.
Go ahead.
Often are you reviewing PR and have.
You changed the scope of your tickets.
Are how often do you mean me
personally or okay, how often are we reviewing PRs
and how much are we changing the scope of tickets?
I'm guessing to get better output.
Yeah.
So still today we review every PR that goes to production code.
We aspire to not have to do that as much, but we want to make sure
that we've got pretty rigorous quality controls in there.
So if the question is like how many PRs are we reviewing?
I think we have something like 24 engineers, something like that.
And I think last we checked it was something like 700 PRs a week.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So PR size and things like complexity and like a lot of metrics for
that have held relatively constant as we've been doing this work.
The big thing that we're starting to talk about
is can we shift review away from individual
PR review into a broader set of like, you own an area,
you define some quality metrics around it, and then you review on like every 5060
PRs or every ten, like define how complex the system is,
making changes on a broader swath
so that you can actually scale with the PR review.
The bigger thing we do, though, is we have pretty heavy agent review
that are like building agents auto respond to.
So by the time it gets to a human,
most of the low hanging fruit is already captured.
And so we spend more of our time.
I think the thing where most people spend most of their time, I keep looking
to a bunch of the engineers to be like, keep me honest, if I'm lying here
is pulling the PR down, building it and clicking through it to
to make sure it works well.
And we're thinking about how can we make that itself an automated flow.
Oh gosh.
Jordan's choice.
Okay.
So he'll talk to somebody.
Hey, you mentioned
having a company brain disease or connected to the agent.
And I think what they agree with you.
But I'm just curious as to what does that company brain look like
because I think we can't solve crimes fermentation and whatever you
so that the architecture of the company tech stack.
But then maybe you're meeting those that aren't useful.
Like where do you draw the line, what's useful to expose
and what's just noise at the end of the benefit?
Yeah. First of all, I love this topic.
This is anyone who's ever been like, I'm going to build my own to do tracker.
I love working on like, agent flows like this.
The short answer is there's no one answer.
It's going to depend a lot on your situation.
And so I think a better if you will forgive me for this, a better answer
or question is like what is a good way to tell what's useful for you?
And so a plug for Tessl.
We basically when you define a plugin
that can include things like a skill and MCP server,
that's usually how you will give access to aspects of your company brain.
And then you just build evals around it.
And so the Tessl tool will help you define simulated tasks like make a PR
that is going to require information from notion or from these meeting notes
or something like that, and then run and just see if it helps or not.
But you don't have to use Tessl for this.
Like Claude code has a built in eval system
that will just spin a bunch of stuff up and try.
And I think that's like the best answer is try it with try it without
and then see what what helps.
Some rules of thumb I find that the raw sources
tend to be better bang for buck, because you're not having
to put a lot of effort into them.
So we use Granola at Tessl,
just a bunch of ads for tools we like using piping
a Granola transcription is almost always useful, especially like 1 to 1.
Like I just finished this call.
Can you do this action?
Oh my God, it feels so good.
There's also so your
like whatever you use for docs we use notion is helpful.
But man it gets stale really fast and the stale information is a big problem.
And so I'd say before you just willy nilly hook it up.
You want some kind of solution or process, which I will admit
Tessl does not yet have.
We are talking about this of like pruning away the stuff that's no longer relevant.
And it's going to be worse with agents because you're moving faster.
Slack is also pretty good,
but I'd say most of these dynamic sources of information, or most useful
when you do a bunch of talking and like, cool, I'm ready to do the task.
And then you just point an issue at that source.
And so it's like, give it access to notion, but then tell it, get this doc,
do the thing in that doc or get this transcript.
Do the thing in that transcript
and go here.
So I think a lot of what you're talking about is like,
if you already have certain practices going back over it.
How do you tackle this for like starting a new project or like new tech
stack, like the software stack entirely is like changing every couple of weeks now.
Yeah. So did you want to come up with, like, a new tech stack?
Like, where do you go from that?
So how does this work in Greenfield is effectively the question.
Good answers.
I think it's a fair bit easier because you don't have to deal with a lot
of the organizational change, which is ultimately the limiter.
So realistically, I'd say pick whatever and just think about your inner loop,
your outer loop and the meta loop from the start.
If you want maybe like a slightly more opinionated the
I see people going one of two ways.
They're either like be super on distribution.
So it's like TypeScript with white
and like react, Next.js, things like that.
And just hope agents get as much right as possible from day one.
Or they go like pick a really obnoxious language that's like really type safe.
Lots of compiler checks.
Like rust is having its moment.
Elixir got a random shout from OpenAI for for a moment.
In that case, that's where I'm going to lean really hard into the inner loop
and try to get like, just the craziest checks in place.
I like that I probably said it as though I prefer TypeScript,
but I have started building a lot of my side projects in rust.
It also has a very integrated toolchain, so like the package manager,
the test suite, and all of that is not things the agent can mess up.
So personally, I think really type pedantic languages
with really integrated modern set of tools.
It's kind of a good way to go.
And then after that GitHub actions and just try to automate a bunch of stuff.
That you.
Want to check whether some problems
keep repeating that somewhere else can come in.
Sounds like what do we search?
We need to go through
all the conversations that happened in the history of the company.
Now, if it's just finding
the agent, context is pretty quickly.
I was wondering if you're using something like vector Search by the case.
Right now?
No, we just use agentic search.
The sort of saving grace here is that to get good output from agents,
you want their tasks to be pretty focused, which tends to keep
then the context that they ingest.
Also pretty focused.
So I wouldn't say like don't have
one maintenance agent that's just like, please make it better.
You want to say like, hey, you look at complexity
of like the last ten years and then make improvements where it seems too big.
Or you look at specifically areas
where test coverage is low and decide, is that legitimate or not?
And so where we see a lot of the industry
going in terms of
like what is software engineering as a profession is actually a lot of
creation of and oversight of these kinds of maintenance agents,
where you will have like a code owner who is thinking about
all the ways that can go wrong, and then creating these guardrails,
creating these checks against it.
But they'll be very fine grained, which will help with that.
And then just the flexibility of agent search kind of wins out.
And sounds like an open to that check
for repeating issues to make sure.
So the check for repeated issues. Is
a of specialized.
Yes. Yeah. And yeah.
Yes. Yeah.
We haven't gotten so many that we're having agents suggest agents
I'm sure come back in six months probably.
But it just kind of keeps moving up the stack. Right.
Then you're you're building the agent that finds agents and it feels durable.
Like, I know some of the sort of superintelligence people like.
Yeah, but eventually you're going to run out of tasks to do, right?
Like eventually the agent's going to do it all.
And my sort of philosophy on this
is that we have had AGI coding agents for 80 years.
We just called them software engineers, and even in that world,
we still needed managers who were technical.
We still needed like
the CEO didn't just set revenue targets and then go home, right.
Like they had opinions about how it should be built.
They had other like PMS, designers, architects who had opinions below them.
And so I think that there is a durable layer that is human taste, human desire,
like knowing what is the right thing to build, and then more and more of the
once you've
sussed out the opinions build it will be agents.
Yeah.
Any questions?
I don't have the cube, so I'm captured.
Maybe you've asked the question already, haven't you?
No you haven't. All right. Go ahead. So what's the.
So I've seen the code review feature commonly recently.
What's the value differentiator between the code review features
code and all the ones that are out there?
Yeah. And or labs.
You got it. Yeah. Yeah.
So the question was why Tessl's code review over anyone else's code review?
The honest answer is like why anybody's code review it.
They're all doing the same thing.
So then to flip that around we use CodeRabbit.
We love CodeRabbit.
We're in the process of replacing Code Rabbit with our own tool number one.
We just think it's like not a very differentiated thing.
And there's not a lot of reason
to pay $25 a PR review for something that's ultimately
like, agree with your team on a skill, and then just check it into the code base.
So we think you can do it a lot cheaper, and we think it's probably something
you should own.
It's part of your engineering discipline.
If you want a slightly more technical answer, we do have this one
concept that we call verifiers, which is you can think of it
as like very small, very cheap, very fast LM powered linting rules.
So you will identify something like every react component
should have an Aria attribute on it.
It's like a very targeted check that you could run
like haiku from three years ago, and it would probably get it right.
Maybe not three years, but you get the idea.
And the idea is you want to move a lot of stuff out of that, like really
big, expensive, heavy agent review into these very fast, cheap verifiers.
And then that lets you do two things, lets you shift it left so you can like
it becomes part of your inner loop instead of your outer loop.
The second is just so much cheaper, like when we we think we have something
like over 100 verifiers running on every PR and it costs.
I'm going to pull a number
that's like directionally correct, but don't hold me to it.
It's like $0.30 to do a full day's worth of PR reviews with it,
whereas it's like $25 per PR for an agentic review.
So that's the thing
we think is like pretty clever and that is relatively differentiated.
And then of course, I think the bigger thing is
it's all integrated into the broader platform.
So you make a code review skill, you can share it on
the registry, you can eval it, you can do other things with it.
Are you binding in deterministic blinkers and other checkers
into the same code review a lot of this.
So most of the processes that we provide are the LM pieces.
But yeah you can absolutely like
the Tessl agent will help you set up your deterministic stuff.
And in creating your agent review,
the first thing that will also help you create your first review skill.
It pushes to say like, hey, check the CI/CD and hey,
if you don't have CI/CD, maybe add that stuff like that.
Yeah.
That's fine.
I could stay up here all night.
Yeah. Thank you everybody.
Do you want to know more?
Okay, I'll be walking around.
Come. Come by me. Thanks, everybody. Thank you.